Personal info

Name: Yajie (Cathy) Guan

Address: Research School of Physics, Australian National University

60 Mills Rd, Acton ACT 2601, Australia

Phone: (+61) 451026951 **E-mail:** yajie.guan@anu.edu.au

Personal Website: https://yajieguan.github.io Citizenship: Australia (Eligible for E3 Visa)

Language: Chinese (Native); English (Proficiency, IELTS [8/9])

Professional Summary

Self-directed and motivated PhD Student from ANU Centre for Gravitational Astrophysics with research background of photonics sensing and laser stabilization. Involved in multiple research projects, including cavity enhanced spectroscopy and fibre array sensing. Having a broad knowledge in applied optics, from physics point of view (including free space optics, optical resonator, fibre, lasers, etc) to engineering prototyping (from software programming to hardware analog design). Demonstrated ability to work in a challenging and fast-paced environment. Having two years of experience in a start-up company working on industrial projects and volume production, especially in charge of hardware design and associated QA/QC test development. Recognized as a strong collaborator with ability of efficient communication with third-party manufacturers (domestic and international). Skilled at multiple programming languages and interested in learning state-of-the-art techniques (such as machine learning algorithms) and utilizing it to solve problems in different projects.

Personal skills

Programming C/C++; Matlab; Python

Languages Hardware Description Language (HDL)

Software Visual Studio; Vivado; Vitis; LTspice; Labview

Multiphysics Coupling and Analysis (Comsol) Optical Waveguide Simulation Software (RSoft) Machine Learning tools (Pytorch, scikit-learn)

AutoDesk; Solidworks

Optical free-space optics handling (lens, PBS, waveplates, etc.)

skills optical fibre handling (stripping, splicing, etc.)

free-space cavity design and alignment cavity mode calculation and modeling laser mode matching; laser stabilization polarization analysis and simulation

optical equipment handling (spectrometers, detectors, EOM, OTDR, etc.)

Electronic PID control system design and analysis

skills electronic circuit simulation

analog system design and testing (ADC, DAC, trigger, etc.) digital system design and testing (SoC, WiFi, USB, etc.)

electronic devices handling (oscilloscope, spectrum analyser, probes, etc.)

Research Projects

Free-space optic sensing	
Cavity Enhanced Laser Absorption Spectroscopy	2015 - 2020
Acoustic sensing using optical interferometry	2018 - 2019
Optical fibre array sensing	
Lead fiber noise reduction using time-delay interferometry	2013 - 2014
Education	
Australian National University Doctor of Philosophy in Physics (Photonics)	2015 - 2021
• Advisor: Professor. Jong Chow	
\bullet Thesis title: Novel cavity - enhanced techniques for metrology	
Australian National University Bachelor of Engineering with First Class Honors	2012 - 2014
• Major: Electronic and Communications.	
• Minor: Physics.	
• GPA: 6.7/7.0	
Beijing Institute of Technology Bachelor of Engineering	2010 - 2012
• Major: Optical Information Science and Technology.	

Honors and Awards

• GPA: 4.0/4.0

2019 - 2020	Postgraduate Research Scholarship
2017 - 2019	Australian Government Research Training Program Scholarship
2016 - 2017	Australian Postgraduate Award
	Higher Degree By Research (HDR) Supplementary Scholarship
2015 - 2016	HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship
	ANU PhD Scholarship
2014 - 2014	Outstanding Graduates with First Class Honors
2012 - 2014	ANU CECS Undergraduate International Scholarship
2012 - 2012	National Scholarship (top 0.2%)
2010 - 2011	University First Prize scholarship (top 1%)

Industry experience

Liquid Instruments	2019 - Present
Test and QA Engineer	
Beijing SWT Science and Technology Co	2012–2013
Trainee engineer	

Major responsibilities and roles

QA/QC Test Development

2019 - 2021

Create the test plan for the manufacturing line; identify quality assurance process; develop automation tests to verify the product functionalities with respect to the FPGA (including the DDR, Bluetooth, EMAC, eMMC, USB, QSPI, JTAG, WiFi, SFP, SATA, I2C/SPI continuity and etc); generate test documents and specification of the product.

Hardware Design 2019 - 2021

Develop hardware circuitry that meets certain functionalities and requirements; circuitry simulations and validations; PCB review.

Project Coordinator

2019 - 2021

Contact and communicate with business partners; involved with project plans and schedules.

Optical device testing

2012 - 2013

Optical waveguide simulation and design; optical fibre coupler testing.

Teaching experience

Australia National University

2016 - 2019

Academic Staff

Beihang University

2012 - 2012

Lab assistant

Publication and Talks

Polarization Impedance Matching Cavity Enhanced Laser Absorption Spectroscopy Y. J. Guan, C. P. Bandutunga, J. Dong, T. T. Lam, R. Fleddermann, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow. *Manuscript Submitted to Optics Express*, 2021

Quantum Noise Limited Trace Gas Cavity Enhanced Polarization Spectroscopy

Y. J. Guan, J. Dong, C. P. Bandutunga, R. Fleddermann, T. T. Lam, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow. Light, Energy and the Environment 2018 (E2, FTS, HISE, SOLAR, SSL), OSA Technical Digest (Optical Society of America, 2018), paper EW3A.8.

Cavity Enhanced Polarization Impedance Matching Spectroscopy

J. Dong, T. T. Lam, R. Fleddermann, Y. Guan, C. P. Bandutunga, D. E. McClelland, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow

Light, Energy and the Environment 2015, OSA Technical Digest (Optical Society of America, 2015), paper ETh2A.2.

Cavity Polarization Mode Impedance Matching Spectroscopy

Y. J. Guan, J. Dong, T. T. Lam, R. Fleddermann, C. P. Bandutunga, D. E. McClelland, M. B. Gray, and J. H. Chow.

Oral Presentation at The Australian and New Zealand Conference on Optics and Photonics (ANZCOP) 2017

Double Pass Cavity Enhanced Absorption Measurement with Scattering Minimisation Y. J. Guan, C. P. Bandutunga, J. Dong, R. Fleddermann, M. B. Gray, T. T. Lam, and J. H. Chow. Oral Presentation at The Australian and New Zealand Conference on Optics and Photonics (ANZCOP) 2015

References

Available upon request